Jing Mai

Science Building #5, Peking University, No.5 Yiheyuan Road, Haidian District, Beijing 1000871 jingmai@pku.edu.cn \(\phi \) magic3007.github.io

Bio

I am a second-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science at Peking University associated with the Center for Energy-Efficient Computing and Applications (CECA). I am a member of the *PKU-IDEA Lab*, advised by *Prof. Yibo Lin*. Previously, I received the B.S. degree in Computer Science and Technology from Peking University in 2021. My research focuses are machine learning-assisted EDA; my broader interests include MLSys, concurrency and probabilistic modeling.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Center for Energy-efficient Computing and Applications (CECA), Peking University Advisor: Prof. Yibo Lin

B.S. in Computer Science and Technology

School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science (EECS), Peking University

Sept. 2021 - Present

Beijing, China

Sept. 2017 - June 2021

Beijing, China

Publications

(* denotes alphabetical ordering or equal contribution)

Refereed Conference Papers

[C1] Jiarui Wang, **Jing Mai**, Zhixiong Di, Yibo Lin. A Robust FPGA Router with Concurrent Intra-CLB Rerouting. 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference (**ASP-DAC**), 2023.

[C2] Yifan Chen, **Jing Mai**, Xiaohan Gao, Muhan Zhang, Yibo Lin. MacroRank: Ranking Macro Placement Solutions Leveraging Translation Equivariancy. 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference (**ASP-DAC**), 2023.

[C3] **Jing Mai**, Yibai Meng, Zhixiong Di, Yibo Lin. Multi-Electrostatic FPGA Placement Considering SLICEL-SLICEM Heterogeneity and Clock Feasibility. 59th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (**DAC**), 2022.

[C4] **Jing Mai***, Zizheng Guo*, Yibo Lin. Ultrafast CPU/GPU Kernels for Density Accumulation in Placement. 58th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (**DAC**), 2021.

Journal Papers

[J1] Yihua Cheng, Zejia Fan, **Jing Mai**, Yifan Wu, Pengcheng Xu, Yuxuan Yan, Zhenxin Fu, Yun Liang. Critique of "Planetary Normal Mode Computation: Parallel Algorithms, Performance, and Reproducibility" by SCC Team From Peking University. IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems(**IEEE Trans Parallel Distrib Syst**), 2021.

Research Experiences

Nanjing Industrial Innovation Center of EDA (NiCEDA)

Software Development Intern

Topics: Dataflow-driven global placement

Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK)

Summer Intern, co-advised by Prof. Yibo Lin and Prof. Bei Yu Topics: Electrostatics-Based global placement for FPGAs Aug 2021 - Sept. 2021

Shanghai, China

July 2020 – Aug 2020

Shenzhen, China

Honors and Awards

 The 3rd EDA Elite Challenge (Second Prize) 	Dec 2021
 Honors for Outstanding Undergraduate Graduates in Beijing (top 1%) 	May 2021
Beijing Challenge Cup Competition (Second Prize)	May 2021
Xiaomi Scholarship, Peking University	Dec 2020
 Honors for Merit Student, Peking University (top 5%) 	Dec 2019, Dec 2020
 Huawei Scholarship, Peking University 	Dec 2019
 Honors for Outstanding Academic Performance, Peking University 	Dec 2018
The 43rd ACM-ICPC Asia Regional Competition (Gold Award)	Nov 2018

Teaching and Mentoring Experience

• **Teaching Assistant** – Optimization and Machine Learning in VLSI Design Automation, Peking University

2022

Skills

Programming Languages and Softwares

C/C++, Python, Java, Pytorch, Tensorflow, MTpX, Git, CUDA, Docker, Data Analysis/Visualization(Pandas)

Web Development

HTML5, JavaScript

EDA Tools

Xilinx Vivado

Languages

Mandarin, Cantonese, English, Japanese